AJ TROXELL

Contact

1409 West Ash Decatur, IL 62526 217.358.9668 aj@ajtroxell.com http://ajtroxell.com

Objective

Creative individual who is always seeking the next; challenge, social interaction, and wave of innovation to further personal and professional knowledge, experience and career.

Education

Richland Community College

Associates in Applied Sciences August 2003 - May 2004

Warrensburg-Latham High School

General Education Degree Graduated 2003

Experience

JTnet Inc.

Interactive Specialist

Prioritize construction and maintenance of multiple web projects. Websites are built using homebrewed HTML or the Foundation framework, CSS/CSS3 structured and optimized for SASS, and constructed using new HTML5 standards and popular practices. Recent web projects boast a focus responsive design.

September 2011 - Present

Creative Media Services

Web Developer/Designer

Meet with potential and current clients to help envision a new or revitalized web presence using the latest techniques and technologies including; social media, content management systems, event management, and advertising.

March 2010 - September 2011

Deckard Property Management

Maintenance/IT

Provided maintenance support using mechanical and problem solving abilities to repair and maintain properties. Tile work, plumbing, minor electrical, carpentry, furnace and water heater repair and replacement, and paint work. Provided in house IT/Networking support for workstations and servers. December 2008 - March 2010

DynaGraphics/Fast Impressions

Graphic Designer

Meet with potential and current clients to help envision creative approaches to printed items such as logos, business cards, brochures, vehicle wraps and advertisement materials.

January 2007 - December 2008

Skills

- Fluent in xHTML(5)/CSS with everyday usage of SASS (including mixins and variables)
 - CodeKit is my tool of choice as its features are outstanding. The Kit language is used to prototype designs/wireframes as well as static websites. All JS and SASS files are compiled into compressed and minified master files for inclusion on the front-end design.
 - o Extensive knowledge of media queries and the Foundation framework (avid user since version 2).
- Intermediate knowledge of Javascript.
 - o jQuery/jQuery UI is used daily for items such as adding/removing classes in responsive designs at specific resolutions, controlling menus and triggering animations, form validation, populating form elements, allowing user controlled theming etc.
- Working knowledge of PHP.
- Intermediate knowledge of MySQL and database manipulation tools such as Sequel Pro and NaviCat to insert, delete, and edit rows and entries.
- Intermediate knowledge of ExpressionEngine.
 - o Custom "theming" and usage of modules/add-ons such as better pages, taxonomy, assets, google maps for ee, low seg 2 cat, and playa.
- Extensive knowledge of Wordpress.
 - o Custom built themes, custom theme options panels, custom widgets and plugins, custom admin themes to match website front-end designs, and other hacking.

- Advanced usage of Adobe products; Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Acrobat, and Flash.
- Advanced usage of CorelDraw.
- Advanced usage of Microsoft Office components; Word, PowerPoint, Excel.
- Experience in digital photography using point-and-shoot and DSLR cameras. Retouching using Photoshop and/or Lightroom.
- Experience developing and producing imagery for vehicle wraps, trade show booth displays, large outdoor graphics, and paper based printed materials.
- Experience brainstorming, sketching, and producing marketing materials.
- Intermediate knowledge of NationBuilder (nationbuilder.com). NationBuilder uses a proprietary theming framework and server compiled SASS. Although great for non-developers, its framework and structure pose a challenge to developers as it is meant as an out of the box solution for organizations and politicians. A personal challenge has been set to create a moduler and highly attractive theme framework for NationBuilder sites to allow easy customization without compromising speed or capability.

Examples

- http://smart-till.com/
- http://ericksondavislaw.com/
- http://www.shavermfg.com/
- http://babytalk.org/
- http://www.triple-c-inc.com/
- http://www.ortho-neurocenter.com/
- http://www.currycon.com/
- http://illinoisadapt.org/
- http://www.wilmingtonhealth.com/
- http://www.hbtbank.com/
- http://physicianshealthcarecollaborative.com/
- http://www.erikaharold.com/
- http://gireroofing.com/
 - single page temporary site
- http://www.balkema.org
- http://www.bluediamondbrands.com/

o single page temporary site

References

A multitude of references are available upon request.

About Me

I am 28 years old, living in Decatur, Illinois with my wife of 8 years, two beautiful daughters, one dog and one cat. Since the age of 13, I have been in love with web technologies and design in all aspects. From the clever use of colors, to the in your face use of typography. Our household is a never ending cornucopia of creation and experimentation. Whether it be hand made clay characters, hand built hardwood furniture, printed posters and decorations, or electrical gadgets and anything else we can hack. We are a family of tinkerers and tailors.

Please have a look at my personal website and blog to find out a little more about me and see what I like to create in my spare time: http://ajtroxell.com/